Hugsney Ferreira

Data Analyst

London – UK +44 7366 711829 hugsneyjc@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/hugsney-ferreira

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Over 9 years of experience in data analysis plus 2 years working with Python, SQL, and Excel. Throughout my career, I have honed strong skills in designing dashboards utilizing Excel, for reports on a daily, weekly, and monthly basis. Moreover, I successfully build programs that automate various tasks, resulting in significant time savings. In addition to my degree in Business and in Software Engineering at Imperial College of London, I am currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in Data Science.

KEY SKILLS

- Python: Openpyxl, Selenium, OS & XlsxWriter

- Other languages: JavaScript & SQL

- Data Visualization: Excel, Looker & Tableau

- Data Analysis: Python Pandas & Numpy

- Soft Skills: Organization, attention to detail

& strong problem-solving

- Languages: English | Portuguese | Italian | Spanish

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science and computing

Oct 2022-Present

Birkbeck, University of London - UK

- FrontEnd Projects:
 - https://titan.dcs.bbk.ac.uk/~hfabio01/travel-guide/home.html
 - https://hugsneyf.github.io/google-page/

Software Engineer

2023 - 2024

Imperial College London - Portfolio Certification

BA Business, Accounting and Communication

2008 - 2013

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst GROUP NEXUS, LONDON

Feb 2023 - Present

- Created Python program using Selenium to automate a refund process. This improvement saved 8 people's worth time and increased accuracy by minimising human errors.
 - Automated the reporting downloads process using Selenium, resulting in a monthly saving of one week of work time for 3 team members.
 - Conducted data analysis on Big Data with Pandas and Numpy, creating and automating dashboards.
 - Develop interactive spreadsheets on Google Sheets and Excel to easily track client call reissues and address financial gaps effectively.
 - Worked on a data migration project from Azure to Google BigQuery for Looker data visualization.
 - Automated reports using the XlsxWriter library for analysis by developing scripts to streamline work.
 - Designed and implemented automated Macro sheet in JavaScript (AppScript), resulting in a daily time saving of approximately 1 hour.
 - Designed interactives maps on google, to produce visual information that brings new insights.

Electronic Compliance Officer HEALTH VISION UK, LONDON

Sep 2020 - Jan 2023

- Provided support in contact between individuals in needy to their careers, working with a team of nearly 400 carers.
- Assessed potential health and safety risks by collaborating with reports information management.
- Analysed large datasets, including over 10,000 weekly calls, to interpret patterns and trends in healthcare. This analysis provided valuable insights into areas such as medication management, mental health issues, and cleanliness problems.
- Leveraged Python and SQL to analyse large datasets from Mobizio and Access People Planner
- Implemented a sprint retrospective action that reduced time spent on manual testing by 20%, enhancing team efficiency
- Embraced continuous improvement by identifying process bottlenecks and suggesting Scrum process optimizations

Data Analyst – Accounts Payable

Sep 2015 – Feb 2019

CORPORATE SOLUTIONS AND TECNOLOGY CENTER - ALGAR, MINAS GERAIS, BRAZIL

- Started conducting analysis that successfully reduced by over 5% the amount expends (around £100k per month) in travel expenses
- Streamlined the reserving process for employees within 5 days by creating new documentation formats
- Automated the data analysis process for travel expenses, saving 3 hours a day by using VBA to develop macros
- Conducted audits of travel documents and receipts, ensuring compliance with regulations and secure archiving
- Managed the volume and deadlines for invoice entries, utilizing PowerBI, and efficiently allocating tasks to the appropriate team
- Improved internal communication and knowledge by delivering training sessions and updating employees on changes
- Collaborated with the risk management team to analyse and mitigate potential risks associated with travel expenses